### Contact

Eindhoven, Netherlands 0648459980 (Mobile) radu.dragan@vinylducky.nl

www.linkedin.com/in/radudragan-0a894172 (LinkedIn) draganradu.github.io/ (Other) www.npmjs.com/package/simplecolor-converter (Other)

# Top Skills

Scrum master
Agile Methodologies
Agile Project Management

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Romanian (Native or Bilingual)
Dutch (Elementary)
Hungarian (Elementary)

## Certifications

Advanced Vue.JS
Introduction to Medical Software
Google - Bazele marketingului digital
Agile SCRUM
Learning Vue.js (2017)

#### Honors-Awards

Innovation Labs - Finalist
Chivas - The Venture - Semifinalist

# Radu Dragan

Scrum Master and Frontend Developer at Onera Health Eindhoven, North Brabant, Netherlands

# Summary

I'm a builder of wonderful digital things, some would call me a maker. Making things is my main motivation for getting out of bed in the morning. Be it front end, back end, or motorbike end, as long as I'm coding/wrenching/cutting/building I'm a happy camper as they say. The simplest way to explain it is: Building the world is the only way we can shape the future.

Front-End Development | User Experience Design | JavaScript | ReactJS | VueJS | UI | Node | Agile | Graphic Design

# Experience

Onera Health
Scrum Master / Frontend Developer
October 2022 - Present (1 year)
Eindhoven, North Brabant, Netherlands

Working in a fast moving start up requiers to have at a time multiple roles. Loved my scrumaster role, mostely because of the team. But i needed to help out and be a frontend developer on multiple projects.

#### Meditools

Full Stack Developer / Scrum master
February 2021 - September 2022 (1 year 8 months)

's-Hertogenbosch, North Brabant, Netherlands

Being part of a small team you have to take on multiple roles. My scrum master experience from my previous job, plays a very important part in organizing sprints and Agile development.

The integration of UX flows, mockups and filling in the gaps using the brand guidelines of Meditools to integrate actual responsive design and make data be palatable to users in a responsive way for an agnostic device design language.

Creating and developing interactive prototypes based on MVP projects in hackathon style development sprints. Integrating the UI design language in Front-End using user story driven development in an end to end approach.

Page 1 of 6

Writing and discussing design specifications for future user flows in the attempt to future proof our app from a scalability stand point.

Integrating and building functional react components, based on components and unit design modules. Maintaining and cleaning mono-repos and git submodules

#### 2Checkout

Frontend Developer/ Scrum Master November 2018 - February 2021 (2 years 4 months)

Bucharest, Romania

Building custom shopping cart applications for an e-commerce platform. The goal is the integration of customer specific business model functionalities with the shopping cart and marketplaces based on the customer branding guidelines with or without mockups. Integrating them in the UX flow based on the UI design language agreed upon with the customer RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Functionality implementation and creation of dynamic content for both Desktop and Mobile devices.
- Develop and maintain high quality code for complex components in the given product.
- Debugging, bug-fixing, refactoring and code review.
- Building email templates.
- Software versioning and revision control using GIT/GitHub.
- Following coding standards and best practices for proper code writing.
- Maintain a close connection with the Solution Architects, QA Team, Back-end Development Team and Graphic Designers in order to agree and to validate the requirements and the scope of the developments;
- Following Sprint plans via Jira and Confluence and commit all status changes.
- constant analysis of web/mobile design standards, trends and usability best practices.

#### **METHODOLOGIES USED:**

- Working with AGILE methodology (scrum team, doing daily stand ups, sprint development of one week, sprint planning, demo, refinement). Use of JIRA for handling tasks, Kanban board for project overview.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### Technologies used:

Vue | ReactJS | JavaScript | HTML | CSS (Sass/Less) | jQuery | Bootstrap | Gulp | Git | NPM | Puppeteer | Jest

In time i was promoted to scrum master in the team that i was performing as a developer. I took this challenge and learn a lot about agile workflow and scrum methodologies. During this period i started to take trainings regarding the Scrum Master position to learn and be prepared for this new opportunity.

#### 4PSA

Frontend Developer
January 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 10 months)

Bucharest, Romania

- Development of one page applications in JavaScript frameworks (ReactJS, ClosureJS)
- Design implementation HTML, CSS, Less
- Application implementation google closure and ReactJS
- Web implementation PHP, javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap.

\_\_\_\_\_

Technologies used

JS | ReactJS | ClosureJS | PHP | SCSS | CSS | LESS | GIT | Gulp | JEST

Hewlett Packard Enterprise Ecommerce Specialist March 2016 - January 2017 (11 months)

Bucharest, Romania

Working in a corporate environment to create UX flows and portal implementations for Continental Europe, Israel and Nordic Countries clients. Creating MVP's to communicate more easily the corporate needs through UI design. Working and training in Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.

Main, Job: sending and verify communication for Continental Europe, Israel.

Main Job: sending and verify communication for Continental Europe, Israel and Nordic Countries (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, bootstrap, SaaS)
Secondary jobs: Photoshop trainings, MVP for communication

\_\_\_\_\_

Technologies used:

JavaScript | ¡Query | CSS | HTML 5 | HTML 1 (email) | Photoshop | Illustrator

Linked Media Romania Managing Partner (CDO) December 2014 - February 2016 (1 year 3 months) Linked Media was created as a 3 way partnership between me and two former colleagues. It was created with the purpose of designing, planning and implementing medical events. My role as a CDO was to create, maintain, grow and provide a digital environment for clients. In addition I created the branding, mockups, interactive prototypes and delivered the final assets. The platform developed was used for training purposes for doctors and to manage the participants enrolled in the events. Page 3 of 6 Our projects:

- Developing a Learning Platform Moodle (PHP)
- Events with:
- Romanian Institute that Protects Mother and Child
- Romanian Congress of Toxicology
- Medical Publications.

#### VERSA PULS MEDIA

Art Director

August 2014 - December 2014 (5 months)

Bucuresti

- Webmaster for internal websites.
- Materials for medical conferences (programs, maps, flyers).
- Web design for internal websites.
- And web maintenance for the internal website.
- Logistics for medical events. -----

Technologies used:

PHP | Drupal | Javascript | Photoshop | Illustrator | inDesign

#### **LUMINA Educational Institutions**

Associate Art Director

September 2013 - May 2014 (9 months)

Bucharest. Romania

- Webmaster for internal websites.
- Graphic design works on all materials related to the International School of Bucharest and all other Lumina Schools.
- Newspaper editor for internal newspaper, and Zaman (Romania) newspaper
- Edit Books built by International School of Bucharest (LuminaMath) Projects i participated in:
- LuminaMath
- Logistics for the event.
- Design and print of all the materials used in the event including the books.
- Photography Club
- Web Design

Technologies used:
Illustrator   inDesign   Photoshop   JavaScript   jQuery
Facemsiteuri.com (Dragan Radu Aurel PFA) Web Developer
February 2010 - September 2013 (3 years 8 months) Bucharest, Romania
My first start
-up was facemsiteruri.com
- Develop websites for various clients. Using PHP and JavaScript.
<ul><li>Build mock-ups and other graphic elements for existing websites.</li><li>Build WordPress themes</li></ul>
- Build UI for various apps
Technologies used:
JavaScript   jQuery   PHP   Photoshop   Illustrator
Square media
DTP
January 2013 - May 2013 (5 months) Bucharest, Romania
Intern.
- I help prepare materials for print.
- Build internal tools for automation of the printing and finishing process.
<del></del>
Technologies used:
PHP   Adobe Photoshop   Adobe Illustrator   Adobe inDesign   CorelDRAW
Quarkxpress
Education

University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest

Master's degree, Business Engineering · (2018 - September 2022)

Universitatea Națională de Arte din București Master of Arts (MA), Photography and Dynamic Image · (2010 - 2012)

Universitatea de Artă și Design din Cluj-Napoca

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Photography and Design · (2007 - 2010)

Constantin Brancusi Tg Mures

High School, Architecture · (2002 - 2006)